J.K.Ramprakash 🕡 Featured

Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Development, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Manual Testing, Programming, Oracle PLSQL, SQL Server, Postgresql, Triggers, Procedures, Functions, AWS, ASP. Net, Java.



Current Location: Trichy Total Experience: 22 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Chennai, Madurai, Trichy

Notice Period: 1 Month

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Divorced

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Application Development, Requirement Gathering, System

Analysis, Manual Testing, Programming, Oracle PLSQL, SQL

Server, Postgresql, Triggers, Procedures, Functions, AWS, Java, ASP. Net

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

6 years of experience with expertise as Oracle PL/SQL Developer in areas of Application software development and maintenance in Oracle environment using Client/Server.

3 years of experience in Microsoft SQL Server 2012 and Manual Testing.

Experience on writing Stored Procedures, Functions, Cursors and Triggers.

Having knowledge on C#, ASP.NET and Postgresql 9.x.

Intended to build a career which encourages being creative, innovative and effectively implement my skills towards the successful growth of the organization and to be a man in all the dimension of the life

Work Experience

Dsm Soft as Software Developer

Aug 2019 to Apr 2020

Client: The Pfizer,India Project Title: Optimization Period: Sep 2019-Jan 2020. Role: Oracle PLSQL Developer

Tools and technology used:Oracle 10g,PL/SQL.

Project Synopsis: Pfizer is one of the leading manufacture of healthcare products and medicines. The search screen displays all the product related information. User can search the product information from millions of records.

The Search functionality will be implemented using a Stored Procedure which will be called by passing the parameter value using Entity Framework in ASP.Net.

My specific role/contribution in/to the project: Translate business requirements into creation of database objects: tables, indexes, constraints, Query Optimization and Performance Tuning of stored procedures and testing the Business Logic.

Ambigai Systems as Software Developer Aug 2015 to May 2019 1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=f887eeafaa7f798c08fbafd793e0ba005a5c08021b405a420547435a5c0...

Client: The Wercs Ltd, Latham, USA.

Project Title: Webviewer Period: Feb 2019-May 2019. Role:Oracle PLSQL Developer

Tools and technology used: Oracle 10g, PL/SQL.

Project Synopsis: A application to store product certifications so that if any product information is needed by the user he can retrieve it by means of the Product id, product name etc.. and also it can be downloaded as a pdf or html file for future reference. Search is done using ORACLE PLSQL stored procedure.

My specific role/contribution in/to the project: Translate business requirements into creation of database objects: tables, indexes, constraints, creation of stored procedures and testing the Business Logic.

Client: Ambigai Systems.

Project Title: Resource Management System.

Period: OCT 2018-Jan 2019 Role:SQL Server Developer

Tools and technology used: ASP.NET,C#,Sql Server 2016

Project Synopsis: This Project Organize time sheet the way that makes the most sense for your business needs, making it easy for your employees to know what they need to track and where and automate approvals accordingly. Track time worked by project, phase and/or task and adds any notes or descriptions required. Allow time tracking to be distinguished by billable or non-billable time for more expedited project and time billing.

My specific role/contribution in/to the project: Translate business requirements into creation of database objects: tables, indexes, constraints, Query Optimization and Performance Tuning of stored procedures, monitored scheduled Jobs, debug and design skills for C# and testing the Business logic.

Client: GS Technologies Project Title: GS Framework Period: Jan 2018-Sep 2018 Role: SQL Server Developer

Tools and technology used: ASP.NET,C#,Sql Server 2016

Project Synopsis: This Project let the user to develop dynamic sites using its own GUI.It does not need any code to build a page. We have customized web tools for user convenience to build a customized dynamic web site as per customer needs. Customer can remodel his sites as per their requirements very easily.

My specific role/contribution in/to the project: Translate business requirements into creation of database objects: tables, indexes, constraints, Query Optimization and writing of stored procedures, debug and design skills for C# and testing the Business logic.

Client: The Wercs Ltd, Latham, USA.

Project Title: Purview Period: Sep 2015-Dec 2017 Role: SQL Server Developer

Tools and technology used: ASP.NET,C#,Sql Server 2016

Project Synopsis: This is comprehensive decision support platform that collects and analyzes publicly available detailed product information to consumers on personal care, household chemicals and food products. Purview works to help consumers identify safe, health and social responsible products at the time of purchase. Purview increases product safety and transparency.

My specific role/contribution in/to the project: Translate business requirements into creation of database objects: tables, indexes, constraints, and stored procedures and testing the Business logic.

SS Computers as Software Trainer Jun 2009 to Aug 2015

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Bharathidasn University Trichy in 1995

PG: MCA (Computers) from Bharathidasn university Trichy in 1998

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
SQL,PLSQL,ASP.NET,C#,VB 6.0.			
Oracle 11g/9i,SQL SERVER 2012			
Postgresql 9.x, MS-Access			
TOAD,SQL Developer			
Amazon Web Service(Dynamo DB,S3)			
Windows 10,UNIX			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Tamil				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time